# Vinício Oliveira

## BIOINFORMATICS | SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Guimarães, Portugal

vinimig.github.io

vinicio.mpv.oliveira@gmail.com

## SUMMARY

Versatile and curiosity driven Bioinformatician by education, with 4+ years of experience in Software Development for High Content Screening + 1.5 years as a Spotfire Consultant in the Pharma Industry. Currently deeply interested in the world of Artificial Intelligence and looking to earn my place in it.

### **KEYWORDS**

Python, R, TIBCO Spotfire, Software Development, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Web Development (HTML, CSS, javascript, PHP, React), Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Life Sciences

### EDUCATION —

#### Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal Master's degree in Bioinformatics, 2015

#### Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal
BSc in Biochemistry, 2012
Erasmus student at Universitá degli studi
di Milano Statale, Milan, Italy, 2012

# Machine Learning by Stanford University & DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on November 5, 2023
<a href="https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/MGBXTKY3S76S">https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/MGBXTKY3S76S</a>

# Deep Learning by DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on March 30, 2024 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ /specialization/YFVXX53SHW4L

# **EXPERIENCE**

July 2021 – October 2022

# TIBCO Spotfire Consultant • BinarySeason (Portugal - Remote)

Development of interactive analysis dashboards with TIBCO Spotfire platform, for the pharma industry, mainly using IronPython, HTML and javascript. Additionally, some simple SQL queries for data retrieval. Gathered requirements and implemented a set of dashboards for the different stakeholder groups within the client company accordingly.

*April* 2020 – December 2020

Sr Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer (Tres Cantos, Madrid)
Research and Development of analytical applications for High Content
Screening and Drug Discovery with the TIBCO Spotfire API (C# and R).
Frequently collaborated with QA team to perform BDD testing. Higher
responsibility in the lifecycle of applications playing a wider role in the
development of the same.

August 2016 – April 2020

Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer (Tres Cantos, Madrid)
Coming from a 6-month internship in the company, integrated the R&D team
for the implementation of R analytical methods for applications under the
TIBCO Spotfire platform. Additionally proof of concept creation was
performed using IronPython. Initial contributions using the C# API and
regular participation in code reviews and contact with QA testing.

### LANGUAGES

Spanish (Advanced)
Italian (Intermediate)